E.J. Sahala (they/them)

III SF Bay Area, or Remote

J +1.408.218.2006

cv@saha.la

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ejsdotsh

https://github.com/ejsdotsh

★ https://ejs.sh

I am a network architect and reliability engineer with 24 years of experience specializing in the architecture, design, implementation, and operation of secure, large-scale backbone, data center, cloud, and enterprise networks, and in developing effective, empathetic, inclusive, and sustainable engineering teams and cultures.

I have a passion for solving infrastructure challenges programmatically through software, and want to use human-first design principles to guide the research, development, and innovative application of modern technology to create collaborative solutions to network operations, reliability, and scaling problems.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Cloud Network Reliability Engineer

Adobe - 9/2021-12/2022

- Technical lead for the global corporate network team to engineer automation solutions for wired and wireless enterprise, data center, and WAN (AS1313) implementation, security, reliability, and operation
- Championed initiatives to add rigor to network engineering practices including design and operations reviews, blameless post-mortems, sustainable on-call, and automating configuration and operation

Senior Network Engineer

Box - 11/2019-8/2021

- Improved the performance, capacity, and reliability of Box's global WAN, data center, peering (AS33011), and multi-cloud infrastructure, as well as leading cross-team initiatives to increase operational efficiency and velocity
- Enabled executive visibility of cross-team projects and network status by creating and maintaining dashboards and documentation in Confluence, Jira, and Splunk
- Partnered with NRE and SRE to overhaul monitoring and observability with Sensu, PagerDuty, LibreNMS, Splunk, simplifying alert configuration and significantly improving alert utility/signal-to-noise ratio

Principal Network Engineer

HERE Technologies - 8/2018-10/2019

- Design, automation, reliability, performance, and scaling of HERE's global on-premise (AS1248) and cloud network infrastructure enabling specialized mapping technologies, location data, and automotive navigation services
- Identified software bugs and rewrote QoS policies to resolve multiple long-standing trouble tickets, reduced packet loss and improved throughput 5-10x globally
- Edge network redesign; hybrid multi-cloud interconnection and inter-VPC/VPN routing, virtualized edge compute/network services (FW, LB, DNS, HTTP/HTTPS, VPN), 100G migration roadmap

Senior Network Engineer

Gaikai/Sony - 1/2017-5/2018

- Network planning, design, implementation, and operation of global WAN, edge peering (AS33353), and data centers for PlayStation Now's game streaming services
- Developed and implemented documentation, process, and training improvements which increased operational efficiency and reduced deployment times by 10%
- Designed and implemented routing and load-balancing changes reducing intra-regional latency 2-4ms

last updated: 2023/08/24 1 of 3 cv@saha.la | +1.408.218.2006

Senior Engineer - Network Strategy & Planning

Microsoft - 3/2014-1/2017

- Led company-wide initiatives to enhance customer experience, improve network performance and reliability, and optimize the existing peering (AS8075), CDN, and backbone infrastructure
- Collaborated with O365 and Field Services to increase customer retention and satisfaction; created and presented training and documentation, streamlined service activation and escalation processes
- Education, outreach, and strategic partnership building at events and conferences (NANOG, RIPE, PTC, GPF); elected to DE-CIX Customer Advisory Board
- Developed capacity management tooling unblocking 60+ site builds and saving \$15 million in CAPEX

Systems (Sales) Engineer

Juniper Networks - 5/2012-8/2013

- Involved with all aspects of pre-/post-sales to a global service provider; developed consultative relationships with technical and executive decision makers, led architecture and design reviews
- Key team contributor in transforming resistance into success to exceed quota, and deliver over \$40-million in sales revenue

Network Architect/Staff Engineer

Infocrossing/Wipro - 7/2010-5/2012

- Definition, development, and implementation of backbone (AS19229), cloud, and data center networks and solution designs for a managed services provider (MSP)
- IP Manager, developed training and implemented process, procured v4 & v6 addresses from RIRs

Principal IP Engineer

Intelepeer - 3/2009-6/2010

Hired to stabilize, redesign, and rebuild the network of a wholesale VoIP carrier (AS32385); led
equipment installs, site builds, and successfully completed migrations improving network availability
from <95% to 99.99%, reducing OPEX by 30%, and increasing capacity 2000%

Tech Lead - Senior Network Engineer

Yahoo! - 5/2007-2/2009

- Co-led the global teams responsible for Yahoo's edge (AS10310), backbone, and data center networks; worked with peers and providers to implement and troubleshoot connectivity worldwide
- Collaborated with Architecture to develop and document detailed network designs and new technology migration plans; implemented those plans with zero service interruption

Principal Engineer

Alcatel-Lucent NZ - 8/2006-5/2007

• Lead Architect on complex solution design projects for New Zealand's largest network and telecomm provider; contributed to ongoing metro and backbone redesign projects

Lead IP Network Engineer

tw telecom - 6/2005-7/2006

- Team lead responsible for lifecycle and vendor management, network implementation and operation (AS4323), and was final escalation for all IP/MPLS/telephony-related products and services
- Installed and configured stop-gap monitoring tools, lowering MTTR and beating the commercial solution by two-years; implemented Cfengine to automate administration of Debian, RHEL, and Solaris

Lead Network Engineer

Terremark - 1/2004-1/2005

Responsible for performance, design, implementation, and configuration of a multi-national, carrier-neutral IXP and data center provider; performed traffic/flow analysis in support of peering (AS23148) activities; mentored junior engineers

Senior IP Engineer

Fusiontel - 9/2002-1/2004

- Sole network engineer; responsible for design, documentation, and 24/7 operation, implemented L2VPN with AToM, configured and maintained routing (AS16525), SIP/H.323 gateways; managed IP addressing, administered Solaris & Debian servers providing DHCP, NTP, HTTP, and DNS
- Authored and presented comprehensive company-wide training; reduced escalations, lowered MTTR, and increased sales closure rate

last updated: 2023/08/24 2 of 3 cv@saha.la | +1.408.218.2006

Network Engineer USA.net - 3/2001-5/2002

• Cabled, installed, configured, and maintained LAN, WAN, and data center routers (AS14454), switches, firewalls, load balancers, and VPN concentrators; managed IP addressing, NTP, and DNS

NOC Technician Various - 9/1999-1/2001

Lance Corporal

U.S. Marine Corps Reserve - 1998-2002

- Field Radio Operator; responsible for set up, maintenance, and operation of communications equipment in the field to establish and maintain secure communication with other units. Secret security clearance
- Squad leader; meritorious promotions and commendations

CORE SKILLS

- IP network architecture, design, and operation
- · Learning and teaching; able to quickly ramp up in new subject areas and then teach others
- Writing for technical and non-technical audiences; design documents, training, blogs, wikis, how-to's
- Cross-functional consensus building and collaborative problem solving
- Interviewing, coaching, mentoring, and growing distributed engineering organizations
- Standards development, architecture reviews, system design, and code reviews
- Technology evaluation and vendor management
- Internet peering and interconnection

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

- Hardware and software including Juniper, Cisco, Arista, Dell, Cumulus, Quanta, PaloAlto, A10, F5, RaspberryPi
- OSPF, IS-IS, BGP/MP-BGP, Anycast, MPLS VPNs, RSVP-TE, VxLAN, IP-PIM
- Public, private, and hybrid cloud infrastructure and connectivity; AWS, GCP, Azure, Linode
- · Development using Go, Python, Bash, Git, Make, Docker, SQL
- Installation and operation of Debian/Ubuntu, RHEL/CentOS, Fedora, FreeBSD, and VMWare ESXi servers
- · Provisioning and configuration management with Terraform, Ansible, Puppet, Nornir, RANCID, Jinja, NETCONF
- IP address planning and management, DNS/DDI/DCIM using Bind, Infoblox, Device42, BBNA/TSNA
- Monitoring and observability using SNMP, netflow/sflow, LibreNMS, Sensu, Zabbix, Nagios, PagerDuty, SevOne

CERTIFICATIONS & AFFILIATIONS

Member, NANOG	2012-Present
Board Member, Customer Advisory Board, DE-CIX	2014-2016
Vice President, Colorado Chapter of the Internet Society (COISOC)	2011-2016
Steering Committee Member, Rocky Mountain IPv6 Task Force (RMv6TF)	2011-2016
Juniper Networks Certified Internet Specialist (JNCIS-ENT)	2012-2015
Juniper Networks Certified Internet Specialist (JNCIS-M)	2006-2009
Cisco Certified Network Professional (CCNP)	2002-2008

EDUCATION

Associate of Arts, Physics

Miami-Dade College